Mss.Rec.84 Mss.Rec.84
American Philosophical Society
- Audio recordings
  - Analysis of verb-adverb-adjective forms taken from Washington Matthews' Hidatsa Dictionary, 1971; 07-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:19:54; Bowers, Alfred W.; Driver, James
    In this program the researcher gives English sentences to the consultant, who then gives them back in Hidatsa. The researcher's English sentences are based on definitions of Hidatsa words given in the dictionary section of Washington Matthews' 1877 book, "Ethnography and philology of the Hidatsa Indians." The researcher proceeds through the Hidatsa entries alphabetically and occasionaly skips entries. Interspersed throughout the program are occasional discussions of miscellaneous aspects of Hidatsa social life and customs. The Hidatsa language is referred to on the recording by one of its alternate names, "Gros Ventre." This Gros Ventre is not to be confused with the Atsina language of the same name. This program was originally recorded on the collector's original tape 76, channel 4.
    Hidatsa Indians--Social life and customs; Hidatsa language--Dictionaries; New Town (N.D.)
  - Word list and usage analyses taken from Washington Matthews' Hidatsa Dictionary, pg. 125, 1971; 07-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:11:40; Bowers, Alfred W.; Driver, James
    Program consists of elicitations of Hidatsa sentences. The researcher's English sentences are based on definitions of Hidatsa words given in the dictionary section of Washington Matthews' 1877 book, "Ethnography and philology of the Hidatsa Indians." The researcher proceeds through the Hidatsa entries alphabetically and occasionaly skips entries. Interspersed throughout the program are occasional discussions of miscellaneous aspects of Hidatsa social life and customs. The Hidatsa language is referred to on the recording by one of its alternate names, "Gros Ventre." This Gros Ventre is not to be confused with the Atsina language of the same name. This program was originally recorded on the collector's original tape 76, channel 4.
  - Word list and usage analyses taken from Washington Matthews' Hidatsa Dictionary, pgs. 125-128, 1971; 07-09; 1.0 .mp3; 00:44:52; Bowers, Alfred W.; Driver, James
  - Word list and usage analyses taken from Washington Matthews' Hidatsa Dictionary, pgs. 128-130, 1971; 07-10; 1.0 .mp3; 00:48:48; Bowers, Alfred W.; Driver, James
    Program consists of elicitations of Hidatsa sentences. The researcher's English sentences are based on definitions of Hidatsa words given in the dictionary section of Washington Matthews' 1877 book, "Ethnography and philology of the Hidatsa Indians." The researcher proceeds through the Hidatsa entries alphabetically and occasionaly skips entries. Interspersed throughout the program are occasional discussions of miscellaneous aspects of Hidatsa social life and customs. The Hidatsa language is referred to on the recording by one of its alternate names, "Gros Ventre." This Gros Ventre is not to be confused with the Atsina language of the same name. This program was originally recorded on the collector's original tape 76, channel 2.
  - Word list and usage analyses taken from Washington Matthews' Hidatsa Dictionary, pgs. 131-135, 1971; 07-11; 1.0 .mp3; 01:02:45; Bowers, Alfred W.; Driver, James
  - Word list and usage analyses taken from Washington Matthews' Hidatsa Dictionary, pgs. 135-138, 1971; 07-12; 1.0 .mp3; 01:21:59; Bowers, Alfred W.; Driver, James
    Program consists of elicitations of Hidatsa sentences. The researcher's English sentences are based on definitions of Hidatsa words given in the dictionary section of Washington Matthews' 1877 book, "Ethnography and philology of the Hidatsa Indians." The researcher proceeds through the Hidatsa entries alphabetically and occasionaly skips entries. Interspersed throughout the program are occasional discussions of miscellaneous aspects of Hidatsa social life and customs. The Hidatsa language is referred to on the recording by one of its alternate names, "Gros Ventre." This Gros Ventre is not to be confused with the Atsina language of the same name. This program was originally recorded on the collector's original tape 76, channel 3.
  - Word list and usage analyses taken from Washington Matthews' Hidatsa Dictionary, pgs. 139-140, 1971; 08-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:20:44; Bowers, Alfred W.; Driver, James
  - Word list and usage analyses taken from Washington Matthews' Hidatsa Dictionary, pgs. 140-146, 1971; 08-02; 1.0 .mp3; 01:44:35; Bowers, Alfred W.; Driver, James
    Program consists of elicitations of Hidatsa sentences. The researcher's English sentences are based on definitions of Hidatsa words given in the dictionary section of Washington Matthews' 1877 book, "Ethnography and philology of the Hidatsa Indians." The researcher proceeds through the Hidatsa entries alphabetically and occasionaly skips entries. Interspersed throughout the program are occasional discussions of miscellaneous aspects of Hidatsa social life and customs. At 30:34 there is a 2-second loss of signal. The Hidatsa language is referred to on the recording by one of its alternate names, "Gros Ventre." This Gros Ventre is not to be confused with the Atsina language of the same name. This program was originally recorded on the collector's original tape 77, channel 1.
  - Word list and usage analyses taken from Washington Matthews' Hidatsa Dictionary, pgs. 153-160, 1971; 08-03; 1.0 .mp3; 01:55:55; Bowers, Alfred W.; Driver, James
    Program consists of elicitations of Hidatsa sentences. The researcher's English sentences are based on definitions of Hidatsa words given in the dictionary section of Washington Matthews' 1877 book, "Ethnography and philology of the Hidatsa Indians." The researcher proceeds through the Hidatsa entries alphabetically and occasionaly skips entries. Interspersed throughout the program are occasional discussions of miscellaneous aspects of Hidatsa social life and customs. At 01:50:33 there is a 5-second cut-in of anomalous music, mostly likely from a previous tape transfer. The Hidatsa language is referred to on the recording by one of its alternate names, "Gros Ventre." This Gros Ventre is not to be confused with the Atsina language of the same name. This program was originally recorded on the collector's original tape 77, channel 2.
  - Word list and usage analyses taken from Washington Matthews' Hidatsa Dictionary, pgs. 160-163, 1971; 08-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:58:53; Bowers, Alfred W.; Driver, James
    Program consists of elicitations of Hidatsa sentences. The researcher's English sentences are based on definitions of Hidatsa words given in the dictionary section of Washington Matthews' 1877 book, "Ethnography and philology of the Hidatsa Indians." The researcher proceeds through the Hidatsa entries alphabetically and occasionaly skips entries. Interspersed throughout the program are occasional discussions of miscellaneous aspects of Hidatsa social life and customs. The Hidatsa language is referred to on the recording by one of its alternate names, "Gros Ventre." This Gros Ventre is not to be confused with the Atsina language of the same name. This program was originally recorded on the collector's original tape 77, channel 3.
  - Word list and usage analyses taken from Washington Matthews' Hidatsa Dictionary, pgs. 163-166, 1971; 08-05; 1.0 .mp3; 01:14:29; Bowers, Alfred W.; Driver, James
  - Word list and usage analyses taken from Washington Matthews' Hidatsa Dictionary, pgs. 170-171, 1971; 08-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:52:10; Bowers, Alfred W.; Driver, James
    Program consists of elicitations of Hidatsa sentences. The researcher's English sentences are based on definitions of Hidatsa words given in the dictionary section of Washington Matthews' 1877 book, "Ethnography and philology of the Hidatsa Indians." The researcher proceeds through the Hidatsa entries alphabetically and occasionaly skips entries. Interspersed throughout the program are occasional discussions of miscellaneous aspects of Hidatsa social life and customs. The Hidatsa language is referred to on the recording by one of its alternate names, "Gros Ventre." This Gros Ventre is not to be confused with the Atsina language of the same name. This program was originally recorded on the collector's original tape 78, channel 1.
  - Word list and usage analyses taken from Washington Matthews' Hidatsa Dictionary, pgs. 171-174, 1971; 08-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:34:06; Bowers, Alfred W.; Driver, James
    Program consists of elicitations of Hidatsa sentences. The researcher's English sentences are based on definitions of Hidatsa words given in the dictionary section of Washington Matthews' 1877 book, "Ethnography and philology of the Hidatsa Indians." The researcher proceeds through the Hidatsa entries alphabetically and occasionaly skips entries. Interspersed throughout the program are occasional discussions of miscellaneous aspects of Hidatsa social life and customs. The Hidatsa language is referred to on the recording by one of its alternate names, "Gros Ventre." This Gros Ventre is not to be confused with the Atsina language of the same name. This program was originally recorded on the collector's original tape 78, channel 4.
  - Word list and usage analyses taken from Washington Matthews' Hidatsa Dictionary, pgs. 174-175, 1971; 08-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:25:17; Bowers, Alfred W.; Driver, James
  - Word list and usage analyses taken from Washington Matthews' Hidatsa Dictionary, pgs. 175-177, 1971; 08-09; 1.0 .mp3; 00:50:45; Bowers, Alfred W.; Driver, James
  - Word list and usage analyses taken from Washington Matthews' Hidatsa Dictionary, pgs. 177-178, 1971; 08-10; 1.0 .mp3; 00:25:30; Bowers, Alfred W.; Driver, James
    Program consists of elicitations of Hidatsa sentences. The researcher's English sentences are based on definitions of Hidatsa words given in the dictionary section of Washington Matthews' 1877 book, "Ethnography and philology of the Hidatsa Indians." The researcher proceeds through the Hidatsa entries alphabetically and occasionaly skips entries. Interspersed throughout the program are occasional discussions of miscellaneous aspects of Hidatsa social life and customs. There is a momentary loss of signal at 11:34. The Hidatsa language is referred to on the recording by one of its alternate names, "Gros Ventre." This Gros Ventre is not to be confused with the Atsina language of the same name. This program was originally recorded on the collector's original tape 78, channel 4.
  - Word list and usage analyses taken from Washington Matthews' Hidatsa Dictionary, pgs. 178-182, 1971; 09-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:56:46; Bowers, Alfred W.; Driver, James
    Program consists of elicitations of Hidatsa sentences. The researcher's English sentences are based on definitions of Hidatsa words given in the dictionary section of Washington Matthews' 1877 book, "Ethnography and philology of the Hidatsa Indians." The researcher proceeds through the Hidatsa entries alphabetically and occasionaly skips entries. Interspersed throughout the program are occasional discussions of miscellaneous aspects of Hidatsa social life and customs. From 35:55 - 41:38 there is a discussion of the making and use of large mortars used for cracking corn. There is a momentary loss of signal at 29:28. The Hidatsa language is referred to on the recording by one of its alternate names, "Gros Ventre." This Gros Ventre is not to be confused with the Atsina language of the same name. This program was originally recorded on the collector's original tape 78, channel 2.
  - Word list and usage analyses taken from Washington Matthews' Hidatsa Dictionary, pg. 182, 1971; 09-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:11:08; Bowers, Alfred W.; Driver, James
    Program consists of elicitations of Hidatsa sentences. The researcher's English sentences are based on definitions of Hidatsa words given in the dictionary section of Washington Matthews' 1877 book, "Ethnography and philology of the Hidatsa Indians." The researcher proceeds through the Hidatsa entries alphabetically and occasionaly skips entries. Interspersed throughout the program are occasional discussions of miscellaneous aspects of Hidatsa social life and customs. The Hidatsa language is referred to on the recording by one of its alternate names, "Gros Ventre." This Gros Ventre is not to be confused with the Atsina language of the same name. This program was originally recorded on the collector's original tape 78, channel 3.
  - Word list and usage analyses taken from Washington Matthews' Hidatsa Dictionary, pgs. 182-188, 1971; 09-03; 1.0 .mp3; 01:30:02; Bowers, Alfred W.; Driver, James
    Program consists of elicitations of Hidatsa sentences. The researcher's English sentences are based on definitions of Hidatsa words given in the dictionary section of Washington Matthews' 1877 book, "Ethnography and philology of the Hidatsa Indians." The researcher proceeds through the Hidatsa entries alphabetically and occasionaly skips entries. Interspersed throughout the program are occasional discussions of miscellaneous aspects of Hidatsa social life and customs. From 15:09 - 22:40 there is a discussion of the Winter of the Bent Man and methods of recording stories in the 1920s and 1930s. From 34:25 - 40:46 there is a discussion of rifles, medicine, and hunting. The Hidatsa language is referred to on the recording by one of its alternate names, "Gros Ventre." This Gros Ventre is not to be confused with the Atsina language of the same name. This program was originally recorded on the collector's original tape 78, channel 3.
    Anthropological linguistics; Hidatsa Indians--Social life and customs; Hidatsa language; Hunting; New Town (N.D.); Rifles
  - Word list and usage analyses taken from Washington Matthews' Hidatsa Dictionary, pgs. 188-192, 1971; 09-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:37; Bowers, Alfred W.; Driver, James
    Program consists of elicitations of Hidatsa sentences. The researcher's English sentences are based on definitions of Hidatsa words given in the dictionary section of Washington Matthews' 1877 book, "Ethnography and philology of the Hidatsa Indians." The researcher proceeds through the Hidatsa entries alphabetically and occasionaly skips entries. Interspersed throughout the program are occasional discussions of miscellaneous aspects of Hidatsa social life and customs. The Hidatsa language is referred to on the recording by one of its alternate names, "Gros Ventre." This Gros Ventre is not to be confused with the Atsina language of the same name. This program was originally recorded on the collector's original tape 79, channel 1.
  - Word list and usage analyses taken from Washington Matthews' Hidatsa Dictionary, pgs. 192-202, 1971; 09-05; 1.0 .mp3; 01:30:38; Bowers, Alfred W.; Driver, James
  - Word list and usage analyses taken from Washington Matthews' Hidatsa Dictionary, pgs. 202-205, 1971; 09-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:33:49; Bowers, Alfred W.; Driver, James
    Program consists of elicitations of Hidatsa sentences. The researcher's English sentences are based on definitions of Hidatsa words given in the dictionary section of Washington Matthews' 1877 book, "Ethnography and philology of the Hidatsa Indians." The researcher proceeds through the Hidatsa entries alphabetically and occasionaly skips entries. Interspersed throughout the program are occasional discussions of miscellaneous aspects of Hidatsa social life and customs. The Hidatsa language is referred to on the recording by one of its alternate names, "Gros Ventre." This Gros Ventre is not to be confused with the Atsina language of the same name. This program was originally recorded on the collector's original tape 79, channel 4.
  - Word list and usage analyses taken from Washington Matthews' Hidatsa Dictionary, pgs. 205-207, 1971; 09-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:38:34; Bowers, Alfred W.; Driver, James
  - Word list and usage analyses taken from Washington Matthews' Hidatsa Dictionary, pgs. 207-209, 1971; 09-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:23:46; Bowers, Alfred W.; Driver, James
  - Translation from English to Hidatsa of Roadmaker narrative, pgs. 375-378, 1971; 09-09; 1.0 .mp3; 01:41:21; Bowers, Alfred W.; Driver, James
    This program consists of a translation from English into Hidatsa of a narrative given to the researcher in the late 1920s or early 1930s. The text from which the researcher reads is found in his own book, "Hidatsa Social and Ceremonial Organization." (See Related Resource.) From 1:21 to 1:41 the recording skips twice, with several seconds of silence. The Hidatsa language is referred to on the recording by one of its alternate names, "Gros Ventre." This Gros Ventre is not to be confused with the Atsina language of the same name. This program was originally recorded on the collector's original tape 79, channel 2.
    Anthropological linguistics; Hidatsa Indians--History; Hidatsa Indians--Religion; Hidatsa Indians--Rites and ceremonies; Hidatsa language; New Town (N.D.)
  - Translation from English to Hidatsa of Roadmaker narrative, pgs. 378-379, 1971; 09-10; 1.0 .mp3; 00:20:18; Bowers, Alfred W.; Driver, James
    This program consists of a translation from English into Hidatsa of a narrative given to the researcher in the late 1920s or early 1930s. The text from which the researcher reads is found in his own book, "Hidatsa Social and Ceremonial Organization." (See Related Resource.) The Hidatsa language is referred to on the recording by one of its alternate names, "Gros Ventre." This Gros Ventre is not to be confused with the Atsina language of the same name. This program was originally recorded on the collector's original tape 79, channel 3.
  - Translation from English to Hidatsa of Roadmaker narrative, pgs. 379-380, 1971; 10-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:19; Bowers, Alfred W.; Driver, James
  - Discussion of the date of the smallpox epidemic, 1971; 10-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:17; Bowers, Alfred W.; Driver, James
    This program was originally recorded on the collector's original tape 79, channel 3.
    Hidatsa Indians--History--19th century; Indians of North America--North Dakota--History; New Town (N.D.); Smallpox--North Dakota
  - Translation from English to Hidatsa of Wolf Chief's narrative, pgs. 397-400, 1971; 10-03; 1.0 .mp3; 01:10:03; Bowers, Alfred W.; Driver, James
  - Translation from English to Hidatsa of Wolf Chief's narrative, pgs. 400-404, 1971; 10-04; 1.0 .mp3; 01:57:18; Bowers, Alfred W.; Driver, James
    This program consists of a translation from English into Hidatsa of a narrative given to the researcher in the late 1920s or early 1930s. The text from which the researcher reads is found in his own book, "Hidatsa Social and Ceremonial Organization." (See Related Resource.) There is intermittent signal loss from 34:03 - 35:17. The Hidatsa language is referred to on the recording by one of its alternate names, "Gros Ventre." This Gros Ventre is not to be confused with the Atsina language of the same name. This program was originally recorded on the collector's original tape 80, channel 1.
  - Translation from English to Hidatsa of Wolf Chief's narrative, pgs. 404-408, 1971; 10-05; 1.0 .mp3; 01:36:22; Bowers, Alfred W.; Driver, James
    This program consists of a translation from English into Hidatsa of a narrative given to the researcher in the late 1920s or early 1930s. The text from which the researcher reads is found in his own book, "Hidatsa Social and Ceremonial Organization." (See Related Resource.) The Hidatsa language is referred to on the recording by one of its alternate names, "Gros Ventre." This Gros Ventre is not to be confused with the Atsina language of the same name. This program was originally recorded on the collector's original tape 80, channel 4.
  - Translation from English to Hidatsa of Wolf Chief's narrative, pgs. 408-409, 1971; 10-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:30:34; Bowers, Alfred W.; Driver, James
    This program consists of a translation from English into Hidatsa of a narrative given to the researcher in the late 1920s or early 1930s. The text from which the researcher reads is found in his own book, "Hidatsa Social and Ceremonial Organization." (See Related Resource.) Start of program through 3:19 consists of previously recorded Hidatsa sentences from prior session that have been spliced together with the English sentences removed. Translation starts up again at 5:49. The Hidatsa language is referred to on the recording by one of its alternate names, "Gros Ventre." This Gros Ventre is not to be confused with the Atsina language of the same name. This program was originally recorded on the collector's original tape 81, channel 1.
  - Translation from English to Hidatsa of Guts' war expedition narrative, pgs. 233-234, 1971; 10-07; 1.0 .mp3; 0:29:52; Bowers, Alfred W.; Driver, James
    This program consists of a translation from English into Hidatsa of a narrative given to the researcher in the late 1920s or early 1930s. The text from which the researcher reads is found in his own book, "Hidatsa Social and Ceremonial Organization." (See Related Resource.) The Hidatsa language is referred to on the recording by one of its alternate names, "Gros Ventre." This Gros Ventre is not to be confused with the Atsina language of the same name. This program was originally recorded on the collector's original tape 81, channel 1.
  - Translation from English to Hidatsa of Guts' war expedition narrative, pgs. 234-235, 1971; 10-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:29:55; Bowers, Alfred W.; Driver, James
  - Translation from English to Hidatsa of narrative given by Wolf Chief, pgs. 225-226, 1971-09; 10-09; 1.0 .mp3; 00:18:16; Bowers, Alfred W.; Driver, James
  - Translation from English to Hidatsa of narrative given by Wolf Chief, pgs. 226-227, 1971-09; 11-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:21:23; Bowers, Alfred W.; Driver, James
    This program consists of a translation from English into Hidatsa of a narrative given to the researcher in the late 1920s or early 1930s. The text from which the researcher reads is found in his own book, "Hidatsa Social and Ceremonial Organization." (See Related Resource.) The Hidatsa language is referred to on the recording by one of its alternate names, "Gros Ventre." This Gros Ventre is not to be confused with the Atsina language of the same name. This program was originally recorded on the collector's original tape 81, channel 4.
  - Translation from English to Hidatsa of narrative given by Wolf Chief, pgs. 227-230, 1971-09; 11-02; 1.0 .mp3; 01:03:21; Bowers, Alfred W.; Driver, James
  - Translation from English to Hidatsa of narrative given by Wolf Chief, pg. 230, 1971-09; 11-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:15:11; Bowers, Alfred W.; Driver, James
  - Translation from English to Hidatsa of narrative given by Four Dancers, pgs. 238-239, 1971-09; 11-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:22:18; Bowers, Alfred W.; Driver, James
    This program consists of a translation from English into Hidatsa of a narrative given to the researcher in the late 1920s or early 1930s. The text from which the researcher reads is found in his own book, "Hidatsa Social and Ceremonial Organization." (See Related Resource.) Signal drops out from original tape from 4:05 to 4:09. In the gap between this program and the program that follows it, three or four sentences of material from the original text are missing. The Hidatsa language is referred to on the recording by one of its alternate names, "Gros Ventre." This Gros Ventre is not to be confused with the Atsina language of the same name. This program was originally recorded on the collector's original tape 81, channel 4.
    Anthropological linguistics; Hidatsa Indians--History; Hidatsa Indians--Rites and ceremonies; Hidatsa Indians--Warfare; Hidatsa language; New Town (N.D.)
  - Translation from English to Hidatsa of narrative given by Four Dancers, pgs. 239-240, 1971-09; 11-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:28:06; Bowers, Alfred W.; Driver, James